Let's simplify the process a bit.
Welcome
to the Process Driven channel.
Hello friends,
today we are going to
talk about
how many types
of carry-ons you can normally carry and what you should keep in mind while packing your carry-on bag.
Usually, all flights will give you three bag
options and you can carry three bags. The
first one can be your handbag or
laptop bag in which you
can keep your expensive things like laptop,
jewellery. The
second bag is the
cabin bag. You
can keep those expensive things inside it. For example, if
you have some expensive clothes, you
can keep those expensive clothes inside it
or you can keep any such expensive thing
inside it which you have
not kept in your handbag or laptop bag or you are not keeping. The
third thing is the third bag which is
called your checking bag. You should use it to
keep things which are
not very expensive and you
can also keep in mind that you  Do
n't pack any daily essentials like medicines in it,
as it's possible that the baggage might get
delayed during transit, during connecting flights, or get
lost. Ensure
you
avoid packing anything expensive or daily essentials. Also,
try to pack it
layer-wise,
clicking an image after each layer with
your phone so you know
what you've packed in your checking bag. If
possible,
make a list of all the items you're packing, or if you have any
bills or invoices for those items,
keep those as well. I know
this will be cumbersome and time-consuming,
but it
can save you a lot of money and time. If
your baggage is lost or
delayed, keep
this in
mind when you're returning it to the checking counter.  You will have to check whether your baggage claim ticket is affixed to the back of your boarding pass
or not.
If your baggage claim
discount is not affixed to your back, then
you should take that baggage claim ticket from the counter
because if any problem arises
with your baggage then the most important thing and the
thing that will cause the most trouble will be this
package claim ticket.
Okay, so first of all you have to check whether
you are standing in front of the correct belt in the baggage claim area
or you are waiting in front of the correct belt.
Okay, if all the passengers
who have travelled with you, all those people who are
standing in front of that belt and everyone's baggage has been checked
and your bag has not come and you have
waited for it for two-four minutes, then now you will
go and whichever representative is standing there,
you will have to
inform that representative with your baggage
claim ticket and boarding pass that you have been
waiting near the belt for a long time
but your bag has not come and the baggage of all your co-
passengers has been checked. So
what will happen in most of the cases,
when you go to the baggage claim area with your baggage claim ticket  You will
fill the form because as soon as you give
the information the representative will
ask you to fill a form, okay, so
like here you will be asked to fill the form for baggage in
which along with the baggage deletion, you will have to
mention what is kept inside the package as well,
okay, so after filling the form, you will have to submit the form along with your
baggage claim ticket to the representative
and when the representative reviews the form,
then you will have to wait for some time, maybe the
representative will ask
you to give that detail also, you will have to
give that detail to him and after that
if he means if you find everything correct
after giving your information, then he will
give you a knowledge receipt for the form that you have submitted, so the
knowledge that he will give you, you have
submitted your form, that receipt will be of
utmost importance, after this,
if they have
not attached your coding pass and package claim ticket in the receipt, then
you should staple it
because it is going to be delivered to you later
or you will come back to the airport
You will have to mention
what you want if you want that
baggage to be delivered to your home
because many times it happens that you are at a
place where you have gone for a day or two, then
your temporary address is
not necessary for
you to stay there till the baggage is received, so
many times you have to give your permanent address
that if you are getting it after two-three days then please
send it to my home, so
you can take my permanent address and if
you are going to stay for a longer time then you can
give your temporary address or you can
tell them that I will claim it at Airport A only
and I will pick up
my baggage from there, for that you will have to
give your email address and your
contact number,
when you give them this information,
after giving this information you can go home with your
acknowledgement letter which is a knowledge letter, so
what happens in this, if you
get the pack after two to three days and the
tag is delayed while flying  Or if you have
not taken insurance for the flight then you
can also claim insurance for that. Okay, so let me
tell you my example, what happened to me.
Okay,
from here I had to go to Rum and from Rum
I had to leave.
I was flying on the latest flight on 15th December. My flight was at the
same time. So, on 15th December, when
I was not flying, I came from Delhi to
Rum and was leaving from Rum to Malda.
I had
my checking package there and he was collecting it and
his colleague had given me my bag clean
ticket there. He had given
me two boarding passes, one for
Rum from Delhi and one for Rum to Malda. So I
reached Rum from Delhi and from there I took
another flight to Malta. But
when I waited for a long time in the baggage claim area in Malta,
my bag did
not come. All the passengers who were to
take the baggage left with their baggage and I kept
waiting for a long time.
After that, I had to go to the baggage claim office
and the
representative there also, I told him about my baggage.  I
told them that my bag had not arrived.
After that, they gave me a form. I filled it out.
They specifically asked for
my boarding passes from both sides, the
back tag. They asked for my email address, contact
number, and temporary address.
I provided all these things to them.
After that, they returned me a knowledge
letter. I received the knowledge
letter. I went home and
two to three days after arriving, I
found a note in my letterbox saying that I would have to
come to the airport and pick up my luggage.
When they tried to deliver it to me,
I was not at home at that
time, so I had to go to the airport.
After showing that note and the knowledge letter,
I got my
tag back. When I was taking the bag back,
I asked them that I had to
buy some items from
Delhi, so
how can I claim it? They gave me
an email address and a
receipt stating that I had collected
this bag from them.  Now I asked him for a claim, meaning when did I take the money back from
him? It was written in the receipt.
When I emailed him on his particular email
address and told him my whole story, he
asked me for four things mainly. Firstly, he asked me for a
knowledge letter, which I had received
in a knowledge letter for the form. Secondly, he
asked me for the one I was just telling you about,
when I took the bag, I had received
a receipt from him. I
asked for the same receipt which I had received. After that, he asked me for the boarding pass and the
claim form, sorry, baggage claim ticket. Along with that,
he asked me for the bills and invoices
of the things that I had bought because of Delhi.
Now, the thing could be anything, it could be a
bedsheet, it could be an issue, it
could be clothes, so whatever it was, so
I provided him with all those
details. After providing him with all those details,
after a week,
he sent me an email in which
he had written, "A, meaning without
going into the discussion of  Settlement: We
want to give you a settlement amount which is the
maximum amount. I had read on their website that the
maximum amount
they can give for those particular days,
so I found the amount to be appropriate, so I
told them that yes, it is okay, please
give me this amount. They gave me the
form, which
I will show you. They gave
me my sister's
details. After filling in those details,
I had to wait for 10 days and they
transferred that amount to my account.
This was an example of baggage deletion. There are many such
examples. Sometimes it happens
that if your baggage is not found for more than 21 days, then it is considered
lost.
In many countries the time is different, that is 45
days,
and what all bills are given for that. That is why I
told you earlier that you should
take an image of whatever you are sending and also
take any invoice, if you have it.
Now another thing can happen that when you are
booking a flight ticket, you get an
option of insurance for Baghpat or Delhi.
If you are taking that insurance, then
this work which you are doing yourself, the
insurance company will do it on your behalf. So,
if you want, you can also take that option. Even if
you are not taking it, you can
clean your things. Directly, there are
flight operators. Whichever flight you are
booking, you can go to their company
and there is a department there. There is a
section of package claim on the website.
Because I will show you for Malta.
Okay,
okay. I hope you
liked this video and found it
informative. If you
want to support our channel, then please
subscribe to the channel,
subscribe to the channel, comment
and press the bell icon for video
notifications.